Henry & Henrietta… the love couple of the
seventies... and the laugh riot of the year.
A New Leaf is a comedy, romance film directed by Elaine May.
After running out of funds, Henry Graham, a carefree playboy, plots to
marry and murder wealthy botanist Henrietta Lowell.
Henry Graham, played by Walter Matthau.
Henrietta Lowell, played by Elaine May.
Andy McPherson, played by Jack Weston.
Harold, played by George Rose.
Uncle Harry, played by James Coco.
Mrs. Traggert, played by Doris Roberts.
A New Leaf is a 1971 American black comedy film written and directed by Elaine May in her
directorial debut, based on the short story "The Green Heart" by Jack Ritchie.
It stars May, Walter Matthau, Jack Weston, George Rose and James Coco.
In the film, patrician New York City playboy Henry Graham has run out of money.
He decides to find a wealthy bride, and finds shy heiress Henrietta Lowell.
He takes control of her finances after their
wedding, and fires her dishonest staff.
He carefully plans to poison her, but even his own best laid plans go awry.
The film was a critical success on its initial release.
However, despite several accolades, award nominations, and a run at Radio
City Music Hall, A New Leaf fared poorly at the box office.
However, it is now considered a cult classic.
In 2019, the film was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United States
National Film Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of bankrupt, camping, dark comedy, botanist, murder.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.